NORTH MAMMON,PENNSYLVANIA
Mammon北部 宾西法尼亚
13 and 0,13 and 0!
13比0 13比0!
Next friday,our children will be asked a question.
下周五 会有人这样问我们的队员
How they answer that will define us all.
他们的答案将代表我们所有
The question is: When victory and defeat,
那问题就是: 当胜利与失败
life and death,hang in the balance,
生与死 尤未可知
what are you capable of?
你们能做什么?
State championship!
州锦标赛!
Number one!
第一! 第一!
Same speech he gives every year.
他的演说每年如此
That's because it works every year.
因为每年都有用
What are you doing? You hate football.
干吗? 你讨厌橄榄球
My brother's on the team.
我哥哥是队里的
You hate your brother.
你讨厌你哥哥
besides,did I ask you not to go to the pep rally?
此外 我有叫你别去赛前动员会吗?
Did I ask you to dump the quarterback?
我有让你甩了那个四分卫吗?
- Very nice. - Come on,guys.
- 真好 - 别这样 各位
We're all tired,we're all hungry--
我们又累又饿
and we all know the second you get some of this pizza,
而且都清楚只要吃一点匹萨
you'll remember how much you love each other.
你们就会记起彼此有多么相爱
You ok?
你还好吗?
Yeah.It's just a little cough, it's not going to kill me.
是的 就是有点咳嗽 死不了人
Thanks for hanging with me.
谢谢你们肯陪我
Always.
一向的
Besides,thank your daddy for leaving us the house all weekend.
此外 谢谢你爸爸整个周末都不在
I need some air.
我要透口气
Give me this.
给我吧
- Polly. - Ye.
- Polly - 在
Go on,I'll be right in.
接着 我马上来
Ok,I'm going to go shower.
好了 我要去洗澡
Ok.
好的
Hey,garbage girl, better not forget to wash your hands.
嘿 邋遢姑娘 最好别忘了洗头
Do I what say polly,or brooke and kelly die.
照我说的做 Polly 否则Brooke和Kelly就会死
Now,get dressed.
现在 穿上衣服
Are you ok?
你还好吗?
What does this guy want?
这家伙想干吗?
I don't know.
不知道
Did you tell him our names?
你告诉他我们名字了?
- What? - He called us by name.
- 什么? - 他叫得出我们的名字
Did you tell him?
是你说的吗?
No.
没有
She's right. He knew our names.
是真的 他知道我们的名字
What does that mean?
那意味着什么?
That he knows us,that he's someone we know?
他认识我们 或者我们认识他?
Well,if he knows us, why hasn't he talked to us?
如果认识我们 为什么不跟我们说话?
'Cause he's some kind of freak!
因为他变态!
If he comes back,we have to fight him together.
如果他回来 我们要一起反抗
Right.
好的
This time,we fight,no matter what. Ok?
这次无论如何要反抗 好吗?
He can't take all 3 of us at the same time.
他不可能同时对付我们三个
We all attack him at once.
我们一起攻击他
Are you sure you're ok?
你确定没事吗?
God! What does this guy want?
上帝! 这家伙想干吗?
To choose.
选择
To choose what?
选择什么?
2 of you will leave this room alive...
你们中间 两个可以活着离开
one of you will die.
另一个得死
You choose.
自己选
B.A.U.,Behavioral Analysis Unit QUANTICO,VIRGINIA
B.A.U. 行为分析科 宽提科 维吉尼亚州
Mrs.Homefeldt?
是Homefeldt太太吗?
Hi.I'm agent jareau.
嗨 我是Jareau探员
Thank you for seeing me.
谢谢你肯见我
- Miles said it was an emergency. - Yeah.
- Miles说是急事 - 是的
She said to give this to you.
她让我把这给你
You played soccer.
你踢过足球
I don't understand.
我不明白
By daughter,polly,played soccer, too,for north mammon--
我女儿Polly也踢足球 代表北Mammon--
the varsity team-- she got a scholarship to penn state.
大学运动代表队-- 因此得到了宾西法尼亚州立大学的奖学金
Forgive me,ma'am.
请原谅 女士
My aunt didn't really explain to me the nature of this emergency.
我姑姑并没有讲明是什么急事
No one is looking for them.
没人在找她们
Here.
看这儿
My daughter and her 2 friends,
我女儿和两个朋友
they've been missing for 5 days,
已经失踪五天了
and I know someone took them, but no one will believe me.
我知道是被人绑走了 但没人愿意相信我
- Missing? - Yeah.
- 失踪? - 是的
This-- this herE...
这里--在这儿...
this is you,right? I mean,you found this girl,right?
是你 对吗? 我是说 你找到了这女孩儿 对吗?
No,no,not just me. The team here did.
不 不 不只我 是整个团队做到的
It's been 5 days now. Can you ask them to help me?
已经五天了 能让他们帮帮我吗?
Because no one is looking for my polly.
因为没人在找我的Polly
Well,as much as we might want to take this case,
就算要接这个案子
we have to be invited by local authorities.
也得要地方当局邀请
I'm sure that this friend of your aunt's is very concerned,
我相信你姑姑的这个朋友很担心
but it just doesn't work that way.
但那样是没用的
I called the police chief.He faxed over an official request for our assistance.
我给警长去过电话 他传真了一份官方委托书
This is brooke chambers.
这是Brooke Chambers
Her father,peter,a widower, left her home alone for the weekend.
父亲Peter是鳏夫 周末将其独自留在家中
Polly homefeldt and kelly seymour were sleeping over saturday night.
Polly Homefeldt和Kelly Seymour 周六去那儿过夜
At 9:35 P.M. During the town's pep rally for the high school football team,
晚上9:35 镇上高中足球队赛前动员会期间
both kelly and polly called home.
Kelly和Polly打电话回家
It's me.
是我
I know this is last minute, but please don't be angry.
我知道现在说已经晚了 但请别生气
Brooke,kelly and i are going to take off on a road trip for a few days,
Brooke Kelly和我要去公路旅行几天
sort of our last adventure before graduation.
类似毕业前最后的冒险
We'll be back friday night. Love you,bye.
周五晚上回来 我爱你们 再见
Kelly seymour left this message on her parents' machine 44 seconds later.
Kelly Seymour 44秒后 给她父母留下了这样的语音
It's me.
是我
I know this is last minute, but please don't be angry.
我知道现在说已经晚了 但请别生气
Brooke,polly,and i are going to take off on a road trip for a few days,
Brooke Polly和我要去公路旅行几天
sort of our last adventure before graduation.
类似毕业前最后的冒险
We'll be back friday night. Love you,bye.
周五晚上回来 我爱你们 再见
- Exactly the same. - Word for word.
- 完全一致 - 一字不差
Both calls made were made from brooke's cell, which has since been turned off.
电话都是用Brooke的手机打的 但此后关了
And there's been no activity on their cell phones or atm cards since saturday.
而且她们的手机和银行卡 从周六开始就没再使用
It does sound like they were reading from a script.
听上去确象是照着稿子念的
And obviously,since the phone's turned off, I can't use it to locate the girl,
而且很明显 因为手机关了 我不能确定她们的位置
but I have an open trap on the number in case it gets turned back on.
但我对号码进行开放式跟踪 以防它再次开机
Ok,guys,guys,not for nothing.
好的 各位 各位 我要说的很重要
I remembery senior year in high school.
我记得自己高中高年级的日子
Isn't it possible these girls just took off on a road trip?
可不可能这些女孩儿就是去旅行了呢?
No.
不可能
Absolutely not.
肯定不会
Polly accepted an athletic scholarship to penn state.
Polly得到了宾西法尼亚州立大学 的体育奖学金
I was a high school athlete, just like these girls.
我也曾和这些女孩儿一样是高中运动员
I was these girls.
我也曾是她们中的一个
They don't smoke,they don't do drugs, they don't drink during the season,
她们不抽烟 不吸毒 赛季期间不喝酒
and they did not jeopardize a fulbright scholarship by cutting school and missing practice.
而且她们不会因为旷课 逃避训练 而危及富布莱特法案奖学金
Ok. I hear you,jj.
好的 我明白了 JJ
It has been 5 days.
已经五天了
There's a chance these girls...
有可能这些女孩儿...
there's a chance we may not find them.
有可能我们找不到她们
- I don't think so. - Why not?
- 我不这么想 - 为什么?
The phone messages.
电话留言
If they were reading from a script,they said, I'll see you next friday,not 2 days,not 2 weeks,friday.
如果照稿子念的 她们说下周五见 不是两天 两周 而是周五
Why be that specific?
为什么那么明确?
My guess is we have until friday to find them.
我猜周五前我们必须找到她们
2 days.
两天
So,are we taking this case?
那么 我们接这个案子了?
Wheels up in 30 minutes.
30分钟后出发
Legendary basketball coach john wooden once said,
著名篮球教练John Wooden曾经说过
"it's not so important who starts the game, but who finishes it.¡±
"谁开局并不重要 重要的是谁完成了比赛"
Hi,I'm sergeant sykes,tom,if you want.
嗨 我是Sykes警官 如果愿意 可以叫我Tom
Derek morgan.
Derek Morgan
Agent gideon,Dr. Reid. Jason gideon.How are you?
- 这是Gideon探员 Reid博士 - 我是Jason Gideon 你好
Hope we haven't brought you folks out here for nothing.
希望你们不要一无所获
You don't believe the girls are missing?
你不相信这些女孩儿失踪了?
It's not really the kind of thing that happens around here,you know?
这不像是这里会发生的事 你懂吗?
You'd be surprised to know how many times we hear that.
你会惊讶我们听过多少次这样的话
Still,I've been through the house myself and nothing looks out of place at all.
尽管如此 我亲自检查了屋子前后 根本没什么不对劲
You talk to chambers,the father?
跟那父亲Chambers谈过了?
- Haven't located him yet. - Is that unusual?
- 还没找到呢 - 反常吗?
Chambers is a lawyer. He's always out of town on business.
Chambers是律师 经常出镇公干
November 3rd. That's tomorrow.
11月3日 是明天
State championship football game. North mammon is finally back in it.
州际橄榄球锦标赛 北Mammon终于回归这个赛事
Show us inside.
带我们进去看看
Chief yates,jennifer jareau, we spoke on the phone.
Yates警长 我是Jennifer Jareau 我们通过电话
- Hi. - This is agent hotchner.
- 嗨 - 这是Hotchner探员
Hi,jeff yates. Hi,judy.
- 嗨 Jeff Yates - 嗨 Judy
Hey,why don't you go on inside and make yourself comfortable.
嘿 不如你进去歇歇
- We'll be in in a minute. - Okay.
- 我们马上就来 - 好的
Chief yates,there's not much of a case file yet.
Yates警长 还没有案件档案呢
Listen,I can't get anyone to agree the girls are actually missing.
听着 都没人相信 这些姑娘真的失踪了
Mrs.Homefeldt certainly believes it.
Homefeldt太太很确定这点
Yeah,well,I wouldn't put too much stock in what judy homefeldt thinks.
是 我不会为了Judy Homefeldt的想法 浪费太多精力
Why is that?
为什么?
She's got a history of mental problems.
她有精神病史
- What kind of history? - Depression.
- 哪种病史? - 抑郁症
Just heard she's even on medication.
刚听说她还在药物治疗
Didn't she raise polly on her own after her husband abandoned her,what,12 years ago?
在被丈夫抛弃后 她是单独抚养Polly的吗 大约 十二年?
That's right. Yeah.
对 是的
If you were in her place, don't you think you'd be a little depressed?
如果你是她 会不会也有一点忧郁呢?
Point taken.
有道理
Chief,if you're not sure the girls are missing, why would you request our help?
警长 如果不确定这些女孩儿失踪 你为什么请求支援呢?
Listen,something happened.
听着 发生了一些事
I'm just not sure what and if it's bad, I'll take all the help I can get.
在还不确定是什么情况, 严不严重时 我会尽力寻求帮助
Plus,your agent jareau can be pretty convincing.
另外 Jareau探员非常有说服力
Are the parents inside?
家长都在里面吗?
Well,kelly's parents are in there.We still haven't been able to track down brooke's father,petE.
Kelly的父母在 但还没能找到Brooke的父亲 Peter
He's-- well,he travels a lot.
他--他经常外出
Listen,these people are my friends,ok?
听着 这些人是我的朋友 明白吗?
They're my neighbors,good people.
他们是我的邻居 都是好人
I don't want anybody assuming that they're involved.
不希望任何人假设他们有嫌疑
We just got here,we're not assuming anything.
我们刚到 没假设任何事
Go ahead.
走吧
You were right,sergeant.
你是对的 警官
No forced entry,no sign of struggle.
没有强行闯入 没有搏斗痕迹
If someone did attack these girls, they chose to comply pretty fast.
如果真有人攻击这些女孩儿 她们很快就顺从了
If there were only 2 ways to immediately get compliance without the use of force,
假设如此 只有两种方法 能在不使用武力的情况下立即得到顺从
that's either the threat of force or previously established trust.
武力恐吓或者预先建立信任感
Whoever it was,it took a lot of planning.
不管是谁 都需要做大量计划
Detailed information about the girls.
这些女孩儿的详细信息
When brooke's father was gone, when the other parents were out.
Brooke的父亲离开的时间 其他家长外出的时间
How do you mean?
你怎么知道?
He knew they'd have to leave messages.
他知道必须让她们留下口讯
With that script,they couldn't talked to the parents directly.
如果用稿子 她们就不能直接跟父母讲话
Close family friend or a stalker.
亲近的家族朋友或跟踪者
The folks here look after each other.
这里的人们互相关心
There's no way an outsider stalker stalked these girls without being noticed.
不可能没人发现这些女孩儿被人跟踪
We have to assume the people who abducted these girls were members of the community.
我们必须假设 绑架这些女孩儿的人是本地人
Would have needed a spot to watch her from.
要有能监视她的地点
Should we expect a ransom demand?
会有勒索电话吗?
Kidnappers who want money contact the families to prove they have possession of the victim.
绑匪联系家人要钱 是为了证明他们拥有被害人
They don't call to conceal it.
而不会为了隐藏
Kidnappers. Are we sure they just haven't run off?
绑匪 确定她们不是跑掉了吗?
It's pretty unusual the girls left identical messages.
她们留的口讯相同 这是很反常的
They feel scripted.
像是在读稿子
- Why would kelly run off? - Here's the thing.
- Kelly为什么会出走? - 事情是这样的
This is a football town, kelly plays girl's soccer.
这是个橄榄球之镇 Kelly玩女子足球
Our son is on the football team.
我们的儿子在橄榄球队里
This week, the football is all anyone cares about.
这个礼拜 大家关心的就是橄榄球
That didn't always sit right with kelly.
对此Kelly总是不太能接受
Should it,gill?
是这样吗 Gill?
Should her being told that she's not as important sit right with her?
难道不该有人告诉她 接不接受她都重要?
I didn't say she wasn't as important.
我没说过她不是同样重要
You never said it.
你从没这样说过
No,it's going to be all right.
哦 一切都会好起来的
She'll be back after the game,you'll see.
比赛结束后你就会看到她了
Come on,i got some tissue in the office.
来吧 我办公室有纸巾
You can see all the windows from here.
从这儿所有的窗户一览无余
Someone's spent a lot of time here.
有人在此待了很久
Aw,damn.
妈的
Has it rained since saturday night?
周六以后下过雨没?
No.
没有
He who seeks the queen of all knowledge, speak and be recognize.
欲与智慧女王交谈者 须先开口表明身份
Garcia,we're sending you some cigarettes.
Garcia 我们会寄过去一些香烟
Yeah,why not a flesh-eating virus? It'll be faster and far less painful.
哈？干吗不寄食肉病毒 更快致死 但更少痛苦
We need some butts rushed to the lab for dna analysis.
要将烟屁股即刻送去做DNA分析
Oh,reid,I love it when you say butts.
噢 Reid 最喜欢听你说屁股了
Send away,sugar. Bang bang for now.
寄过来吧 宝贝 先挂了
Do you really think someone from our town's involved in this?
你们不会真信镇上的人 跟这事有关系吧？
You said it yourself, an outsider would have been noticed.
你自己说的 外人会引起注意
Sergeant sykes.
Sykes探员
What?
什么?
Looks like chief yates won himself a title back in the day.
看来Yates警长有着非常光辉的过去
- They do like their football. - Trust me,it's like a religion.
- 就像他们的球队一样 - 相信我 这就像一种宗教信仰
Do you think it strange that with 3 girls missing,
在有三个女孩消失的情况下
nobody's talking about canceling tomorrow night's game?
居然没人提出要取消明晚的比赛 这未免太古怪了
Come on,hutch,it's football. They know they can play without girls.
拜托 Hutch 这可是橄榄球 没女生他们照样玩
Just found brooke's car,abandoned.
刚找到了Brooke的车 被丢弃了
I'm freezing.
我快冻死了
We're all cold,we're all hungry.
我们都又冷又饿
She has a fever.
她发着烧
Complaining about it isn't going to make it any better.
抱怨又不能解决问题
Do you have to be so mean?
有必要这么刻薄吗?
Mean? Some jerk puts us in a box,and I'm mean?
刻薄? 有变态把我们锁在笼子 你居然说我刻薄?
You don't see brooke and me jumping on you about it.
Brooke和我并没有指责你!
I don't see you or brooke a doing a damn thing!
你和Brooke也没干其他事!
Guys,this is what he wants.
嘿 别中了他的圈套
How long have we been down here?
我们在这儿多久了?
We don't even know where here iS.
我们甚至不知道这里是哪儿
He doesn't want us to know.
他不想让我们知道
He wants to break us down.
他要让我们崩溃
It's called sensory depravation.
叫做感官衰退
Well,it's not going to work!
好吧 那起不了作用!
You hear me,you son of a bitch?! It's not going to work!
听见没有 你这狗娘养的 没用的!
Yes,it will.
不 会有用的
If he doesn't give us water and food...
如果他不给我们水和食物...
it will work.
会起作用的
We could die down here.
我们会死在这儿
It's covered in dust. It must've been here for quite a while.
都落满灰了 在这儿有一阵子了
So much for the spontaneous road trip.
自发公路旅行的说法不成立了
This isn't a very traveled area.
这个地方来人不多
Not really.
也不算是
So,the car's left in town where it would eventually be found.
所以 车被扔在镇上 慢慢会被人找到的
Eventually.
慢慢地
Gideon,it's from the football team.
Gideon 这是球队的
It says K.E. On the brim.
边缘上绣着K.E.
- Could be kip engler. - Who?
- 可能是Kip Engler - 谁?
Ah,he's the quarterback. He and brooke were an item.
他是球队的四分卫 和Brook过去是一对
What,you think he had something to do with this?
你觉得他跟这事有关系?
Was he at the pep rally saturday night?
他去了周六晚的动员会了吗?
- Yeah,he was the star of it. - Then no.
- 当然 还是当晚的明星 - 那就没关系
But I think we know the kind of person we're looking for.
但想来我知道要找的是哪种人
Brooke kelly and polly have been missing for 5 days.
Brooke Kelly和Polly失踪已有五天
Usually in cases like this we wouldn't expect to find them alive.
一般来说 生还的希望很渺茫
However,in this case,we don't believe that to be true.
但这一次 我们却不这么认为
The person responsible spent considerable time and energy planning the abduction.
犯案人耗费了大量的时间和精力准备这次绑架
He did not do all this work to simply kill the girls once he had them.
绝不是为了立刻杀死她们
Otherwise,he would've done it at the chamber's house.
不然 在Chamber家就可以下手了
He certainly seemed to know he had the time.
他笃定自己时间充裕
And he had kelly and polly reference friday in the messages they left for their parents.
还让Kelly和Polly在给父母的留言中 特别提到了星期五
We think the unsub has something planned for the night of your championship game.
我们认为嫌犯在决赛当晚有自己的计划
We are certain the unsub is someone from this community.
也很肯定嫌犯是本地人
How do you know that?
你怎么知道的?
Because,Mr. Chambers,he didn't have your daughter leave you a phone message or a note,did he?
因为 Chambers先生 他没让你女儿 给你留言或写便条 对吧？
Not that I know of.
至少我没收到
'Cause he knew you'd be out of town for a while.
因为他知道你要离镇一段时日
Just like he knew the dump site for the car would eventually be found.
就像他选择的弃车处 车子慢慢会被人发现的
Everything points to him giving himself time.
每条相关的线索都给了他时间
Time for what?
来做什么?
- I don't know yet,sir. - Well,what's been done about it?
- 尚且不知 先生 - 那你们又做了哪些应对之策?
Sir,I'm with the fbi. We're going to need some information.
先生 我是FBI探员 我们需要一些信息
Wait a minute.
等一下
If someone from this town's taken my brooke, I want to know what the hell's being done about it.
如果是镇上的人抓走了我的Brooke 我要知道你们到底如何应对
Yes,I know,sir.If you'd just come with me. I will explain everything.All right?
完全理解 先生 请跟我来 我会完整地给您解释 行吗？
Thank you.
谢谢
Predatory abductors like this unsub are intelligent,patient,and cautious.
掠夺型绑匪大多聪明 耐心 谨慎
They like to watch everything-- the victims,the families,the police.
倾向于观察受害人的一举一动 包括他们的家庭 还有警方
He's surely watching us now and may even attempt to inject himself into our investigation.
现在 他肯定在暗中看着我们 甚至试图把自己弄进我们的调查
We also know that predatory abductors prepare a nest prior to the abduction.
还有 掠夺型绑匪在犯案前 会先备下一处巢穴
A remote cabin,an underground bunker,
偏僻的小木屋 地下仓库
a safe and secure place that only he has access to.
一个只有他能进出的安全所在
Designed to confine and conceal his prey once his hunting is done.
一旦作案成功 这个地方正适合关押被害人
Should we be looking for this nest?
我们不该去找这个巢穴吗?
You'd never find it.
你永远也找不到
For his nest,predatory abductor john jemelske built
为了造窝 掠夺型绑匪John Jemelske
a sophisticated dungeon complex under a suburban syracuse home,
在锡拉库扎郊区地下 建了一处精密的复合地牢
where he documented every detail of torture he carried out upon the victims he kept there for 3 years.
他把被害人一关三年 详细记录了折磨他们的每个细节
The man who kidnapped these girls has a relationship or
绑架了这些女孩的人 要么通过私人关系
a job that permitted them to get close enough to watch them.
要么通过工作 接近并观察她们
We must focus on those people who had access.
要特别注意有这样机会的人
A family member,a teacher, a next door neighbor,it sounds clich?
家庭成员 教师 隔壁邻居 听上去很老套吧？
but often it is the person you least suspect.
但通常这些人是你最不会怀疑的
One more thing to remember.
还有一件事
We're looking for someone who was not at the pep rally.
我们要找的人没去动员会
Ask the community,I'm sure somebody videotaped it.
问一下社团 肯定有人拍了录像
You can go through the tapes, start eliminating townspeople.
可以看一边录像 开始排除当地人的嫌疑
I'm sorry,sir. Mr. Chambers just took off.
对不起 长官 Chambers先生刚刚离开了
- Where did he go? - I don't know.
- 去哪儿了? - 不知道
That was garcia.She just ran the cigarette butts through codus and got a name--
是Garcia 她刚在指纹系统里查了烟头上留下的DNA 得到了一个名字
donald haas?
Donald Haas?
Don haas is the girls' soccer coach.
Don Haas是女孩们的教练
Was coach haas at the pep rally?
他去了赛前动员会没?
I don't remember seeing him there,no.
我不记得在那儿看到他
Where would coach haas be right now?
Haas教练现在会在哪儿?
Now,I know that we're all upset about polly and brooke and kelly,
我知道大家都很担心Polly Brooke和Kelly
but it is important that we keep a positive attitude.
但重要的是 保持积极的态度
Those girls,they'd want you to be strong.
那些女孩 希望你们坚强
They'd want your prayers.
希望你们为她们祈祷
Where's my daughter,you son of a bitch?
我女儿在哪儿 狗娘养的?
I get the charge dropped, and this is what you do for me?
我让对方撤了诉 这就是你的回报？
- Take it easy,take it easy! - He did it before in pittsburgh!
- 冷静点 冷静点! - 以前在匹茨堡他也这么干过!
He was arrested,and I got him off. I got you off,you son of a bitch.
他被逮捕了 我把他弄了出来 我救了你 你这个混蛋
That's enough!
够了!
Little help!
帮个忙
Are you okay?
你还好吧?
They're all turning on each other.
他们都互相猜疑
I'm hungry.
我好饿
Remember when we played ashland?
记得我们跟Ashland打的时候吗?
You stopped like a hundred shots on goal?
你差不多射了一百次门?
It wasn't a hundred.
没有一百次
You were on fire that day.
那天你状态极佳
You're the great player,polly.
你是最棒的 Polly
You're the one going to penn state.
你会去宾西法尼亚州大学的
You're going to come visit me,right?
你会来看我的 对吗？
There's got to be a way to get him to come down here.
一定要想办法把他弄下来
He's not coming down.
他不会下来的
You know,some of us are trying to come up with solutions,brooke.
听着 我们中有人正在想办法逃生 Brooke.
Don'T. She's sick.
别 她病了
She's sick,she's sick.
她病了 她病了
What about me? I'm sick!
那我呢？我也快疯了
I'm sick of trying to come up with a plan while little miss perfect over here just whines.
我在想办法出去 旁边的大小姐却在怨天尤人 真叫我发疯
She has a plan.
她已经有了打算
What are you talking about?
你在说什么?
She already has a plan.
她已经有了主意
Why hasn't she told us?
为什么不告诉我们?
Because I'm not sick enough yet.
因为我病得还不够厉害
Hey.
嘿
What the hell is wrong with pete,huh?
Pete到底出什么事了 啊？
Going crazy like that.
疯成那样
Like I had something to do with this.
好像我跟这事有关系似的
- Mind if I smoke? - Yes.
- 介意我抽烟么? - 是的
You smoke more than 100's,Mr. Haas?
Haas先生 你吸加长型的烟?
Yeah.
没错
We found 13 morley 100 cigarette butts
我们找到13支Morley加长香烟头
with your dna on them across the street from the chamber's house.
都带有你的DNA 就在Chamber家房子对面
This is a mistake.
这是个错误
Somebody has made a mistake.
有人陷害我
You smoke those cigarettes and left something for yourself on them,sir.
吸烟时你在烟头留下了痕迹 先生
That's a fact.
事实就是如此
Yeah,but I did not leave them there.
对 但我没扔在那儿
- Can you tell me who did? - How the hell should I know?
- 能告诉我谁干的吗? - 我怎么可能知道啊?
All right,thanks. You can go back to work now.
好的 谢谢 你可以回去工作了
THE SAGINAW MOTEL.
萨吉诺旅馆
Here's the guest registry.
这是客人登记簿
All right.
好的
I'll get started running these names through the computer.
我会开始联网核对这些名字
There's a name in there,john sherman, you're not going to find it in the state computer.
有一个名字 John Sherman 电脑里是找不到他名字的
He stays here once a month,and he pays me $100 cash over the rate so i'll look the other way.
他一个月来一次 多付我100现金 叫我别多嘴
And you don't ask for I.D.?
你也不问清身份?
Well,I don't have to... see,because I know the guy.
呃 也不需要 其实 我也认识他
Only his name's not sherman.
不过他不叫Sherman
It's chambers. Peter chambers.
叫Chambers Peter Chambers
Don haas kidnapped my daughter.
Don Haas绑架了我的女儿
Now,why are you wasting time talking to me?
你们干吗费时间跟我谈?
He's being questioned in another room.
他在另一个房间受审
Tell me why you're so convinced that it was him.
说说看 为什么你这么肯定是他干的
He said it was someone from this community.
他说是本地人干的
The only person I know capable of doing something like this is don.
我知道唯一能干出这事来的人 就是Don
What do you mean,capable?
什么叫能干出这事?
He's a sex offender.
他是个性罪犯
His record is clean.
记录上没有前科
Yeah,well,6 years ago,don called me from pittsburgh
好 六年前 Don从匹兹堡打电话给我
and he'd been arrested for soliciting an underage prostitute.
他因引诱未成年妓女而被捕
Why did he call you?
为什么打给你?
Because I'm a lawyer.
因为我是律师
We'd been friends for 30 years.
我们有30年的交情
We played football together in high school.
高中时是球队的队友
So,why did you agree to help him?
为什么答应帮他?
'Cause don swore it was a one-time thing.
他发誓这事绝没有下回
The guy was going through a divorce,the girl had a record.
他正离婚 而那个女孩还有前科
I made sure that a sex offender could still spend all his working hours around young girls.
我明白一个性罪犯仍会在工作时 和年轻姑娘接近
God,I practically gave him my daughter.
天啊 我几乎就是把女儿送到他面前
Chambers represented haas in a minor sex offense case 6 years ago,
6年前一件次要性侵犯案中 Chambers是Haas的代表律师
had the record expunged.
撤销了纪录
What kind of sex offense?
性侵犯的对象是?
An underage prostitute.
未成年妓女
Sounds like the right kind of crime?
像是正要找的犯罪类型?
Could be.
可能是
Well,haas swears he didn't put the cigarette butts there.
Haas发誓他没把烟头扔在那儿
Does it strike anyone else as grossly inconsistent
有一处明显矛盾 难道大家不奇怪吗？
that an unsub this sophisticated and
这个嫌犯如此精细
methodical would leave an obvious pile of his dna at the crime scene?
如此依计行事 竟会在犯罪现场留下大量自己的DNA？
Don haas was at the pep rally.
Don Haas去了动员会
I saw him in 2 different video tapes.
两个录影带里都有他
I guess I must've missed him.
我猜我大概没看见他
All 3 of the victims' soccer jersies were found behind
三个受害者的球衣
the motel peter chambers has been staying at for the last week.
都在Peter Chambers上周住过的旅馆里找到了
Don haas has an alibi for the night your daughter was taken.
Don Haas在你女儿失踪当天有不在场证明
-What? -Video.
- 什么? - 录影带
At the exact time the other girls were leaving their scripted messages,
就在女孩们留口信的同时
he was at the pep rally.
他在动员会上
Oh,my god.
哦 天啊
You said you were in philadelphia on business last week.
你说上周出公差去了费城
I'm sorry?
什么?
Were you in philadelphia?
你在费城吗?
You think I hurt my daughter?
你认为我伤害自己的女儿?
We just found the girls' soccer uniforms behind the saginaw motel.
我们刚在萨吉诺旅馆后找到了三个女孩的球衣
What?
什么?
Were you in philadelphia on business last weekend?
上个礼拜你在费城出差吗?
No.
不
Where were you?
那在哪儿?
I was at the saginaw motel.
萨吉诺旅馆
What were you doing there?
你去哪儿做什么?
I meet a friend there once a month.
和一个朋友一个月见一次面
Actually,he's more than a friend.
事实上 不止是朋友
This is a small town.
这是个小镇
These are small town people.
都是些小镇居民
They're wonderful in many ways,but there are some things they just don't understand.
他们在很多方面都很好 但总有无法理解的事物
I need a name.
给我名字
Glenn donahue.
Glenn Donahue
He lives on rittenhouse square...
他住在雷登屋广场...
with his wife...
还有他妻子...
and his 2 little boys.
和两个儿子
These men are innocent.
他们是无辜的
You're sure?
你肯定?
Unsub planted evidence to implicate them.
嫌犯栽赃陷害了他们
Forensic countermeasures.
法证鉴定
So,we've got no suspects,no reliable evidence,we've got nothing.
所以 我们没有嫌疑人没有证据 什么都没有
We have the behavior.
但有行动模式
The fact of the countermeasures.
法证鉴证的结果
He tried to implicate haas and chambers.
他想要陷害Haas和Chambers
That would mean haas and chambers had significance to him,right?
说明Haas和Chambers对他意义非凡 对吧？
Who he's implicated may be as important as who he's abducted.
他陷害的和他绑架的对象 也许意义同样重大
He's been watching them all for a long time.
他观察他们许久了
See them.
注意他们
We need to bring the parents and the people he implicated in.
我们需要把他陷害的人都找来
They,along with the girls,are his targets,
他们和女孩都是他的目标
and it may be the key to finding him before it's too late.
在为时未晚前 或许是找到罪犯的关键
He's ahead of us.
他领先了
Has been all along.
遥遥领先
I got a bad feeling about this one.
我有很不祥的预感
Me,too.
我也是
I know it's terrible,but she's sick,
我知道这样不对 但她病了
and pretty soon you will be,too.
我们也会的 很快
I'm not listening.
我不想听
She is dying already.
她已经奄奄一息了
What?
什么?
You don't know that.
你怎么知道
Look at her,polly.
看看她 Polly
She isn't going to make it.
她挺不过去的
We have to face facts.
我们要面对现实
She's dying.
她快死了
No she's not.
不 她没有
Yes,she is.But we don't have to.
是的 但我们没必要陪葬
So,what we have to do is sacrifice our friend and we're safe.
所以我们就该牺牲朋友换取自己的性命
We didn't do that to her,ok?
这不是我们的错 行吗?
How do you know he'll let us go anyway?
你怎么知道他会让我们走?
Did you ever think of that?
你想过没有?
What if he's just some evil,
假如他心肠恶毒
twisted psycho who gets off watching people fight with each other.
是个想看人们互相搏斗的心理变态
Maybe we can get her help if we st get out of here.
如果我们能出去 或许还能救她
He said one of us has to die.
他说我们中间必须死一个
If we don't choose,we are never going to see our families again,ever.
如果不做选择 就再也见不到家人了 再也不
No one will ever know what happened to us,
没人会知道我们身上发生的一切
we'll starve to death and no one will ever know.
我们会渐渐饿死 谁也不会知道
You'll never see your mother again,ever.
你再也见不到你妈妈了 再也不
My mom would be totally alone.
我妈妈会孤零零的
Totally alone.
孤零零的一个人
There's no other choice,is there?
没别的选择了吗?
No,polly,I'm sorry,but there is no other choice.
没了 Polly 对不起 但我们别无选择
She's going to die anyway,right?
她总归要死的 对吧?
That's right,but we don't have to.
没错 但我们不会
All right.
好吧
Ok.
好
Hey,mister.
嘿 先生
We made our choice.
我们选好了
God.
天啊
No.
不
What's happening?
怎么了?
Nothing,brooke.
没事 Brooke.
Nothing.Go back to sleep.
没事 继续睡吧
This unsub,or unknown subject,is someone you know.
这个嫌犯 或称未知嫌疑人 你们都认识
He's someone from your past,
过去和他打过交道
and he's someone who thinks that you have wronged him.
而他认为你们错待了他
We'd like for you to think about who might fit that description.
你们想想有没有符合这些描述的人
Don't you think if we knew who we did this or why we would've told you?
如果我们知道是谁做的 会不告诉你吗?
Please,let him talk,gill.
让他说完 Gill
Oh,I'm going to take advice from somebody on mental medication?
现在我是要接受精神病患者给我的建议?
What?
什么?
Everyone knows,judy.
大家都知道 Judy
Could we just stay focused,please?
我们能讲重点吗?
The man who took your daughters.
绑走你们女儿的人
He framed don haas and peter chambers for a reason.
他陷害Don Haas和Peter Chambers 是有原因的
This is an attack on you.
是对你们的攻击
I have made mistakes in my life,but why take it out on brooke?
我确实犯过错 但为什么要绑架Brooke呢?
You know,it's one thing for brooke to pay for your mistakes,
Brooke替你还债 这不为过
but if my daughter has to pay for them,too--
但如果我女儿也要付出代价...
Mr. Seymour,that's not helping.
Seymour先生 别这么说
That's not fair,gill.
这不公平 Gill
Fair?
公平?
You shut the hell up,you're nothing but a pervert.
你他妈的闭嘴 性变态!
You will never get near the children of this town again.
你别想再接近这里的孩子们
We need to keep this as civil as possible.
我们尽量文明一点
Gill,are you even listening?It wasn't don.
Gill 你在听吗? 不是Don
He had nothing to do with it.
他和这事无关
You knew he was a deviant,you didn't tell us.
你知道他变态 还不告诉我们
We let him coach our girls.
还让他教我们的女儿
His arrest was a sunderstanding,ok?
他被捕的事只是误会 懂吗?
We talked to the hotel manager,peter.
我们跟旅馆经理谈过 Peter
We know about you.
我们知道你的事
Maybe this is god's punishment.
也许是上帝在惩罚
Oh,punishment.
噢 惩罚
Ok.
好
At least I didn't spend the week my daughter
至少我女儿失踪的这个星期
was missing focusing on my son and the damn football game!
我没有只顾着我儿子 和这该死的橄榄球比赛!
No,we know what you spent the week doing.
没错 我们知道你怎么过的
I blame myself for ever letting kelly be friends with brooke and polly to begin with.
都怪我自己 早知就不该让 Kelly和Brooke还有Polly交朋友
Low breeding always shows through.
低等人种总会出事的
Low breeding?
低等人种?
They're bad seeds.
都是些坏胚子
They always have been.
一直都是
Don't talk about my daughter like that,all right?
不许这样说我女儿  明白吗?
That's enough!
够了!
What is the matter with you people?
你们这是在干吗?
This is exactly what he wants.
他所要的正是这个
He is attacking all of you.
他的目标是你们所有人
He is turning all of you against each other,and you're just letting him do it.
他让你们反目成仇 相互攻击 而你们就任由他摆布?
Your daughters are best friends,
你们的女儿是最好的朋友
and you all have known each other most of your lives as friends.
这些年来 你们也都和睦相处
Don't let this man beat you this way.
别让他这样打败你们
What do you want us to do?
你要我们怎么办?
Listen to these agents,all right?
听这些探员的话 好吗?
They came here to help.Let them do that.
他们是来帮忙的 请你们配合
We're going to split you up,
我们会将你们分开
go over your histories,
查一下历史纪录
and see if there's a name from your past in common.
看看有没有共同认识的人
Probably won't be a casual acquaintance.
也许不是熟人
He knows your secrets.
但他知道你们的秘密
Don't just think people you've knowingly wronged.
不要只想你们错怪了哪些人
It may be something you're not even aware of,or you may have forgotten--
也许你们根本没有意识到他 或者已经淡忘...
agent gideon.
Gideon探员
It's penelope garcia from quantico.She says it's urgent.
Penelope Garcia从Quantico打来的 她说很紧急
Put her on speaker.
免提通话
Go ahead,garcia.
说吧 Garcia
Brooke chamber's phone just switched back on.
Brooke Chamber的手机又有电了
Tell me you got a trace.
你跟踪到了吧
And a location.Downtown north mammon,
地点都找到了 Mammon北部城中心
within 100 meters of the intersection of main and first.
在主通道和第一道交界处100米内
That's right outside.
马上行动!
-Morgan. -Yeah.
- Morgan - 在
You keep the parents *********
把家长留在后面 只有两个女孩回来
what's going on?
怎么了?
Back up.Come on.*******
退后 快点
It's ok.
没事了
We're with the fbi.Are you all right?
我们是FBI 你还好吗?
Polly,are you hurt?
Polly 你有受伤吗?
She's bleeding.
她在流血
It's not her blood.
不是她的血
Brooke.
Brooke
Where's kelly seymour?
Kelly Seymour呢?
Let me get you some more water.
我再给你倒点水吧
I'll get it.
我来
Polly,do you know who did this to you?
Polly 你知道是谁做的吗?
Whatever happened...
不管发生了什么...
you're a very brave woman.
你是个勇敢的姑娘
Not many people can face what you did and...
不是所有人都能像你一样面临绝境...
make it out the other side.
而又得以战胜的
It wasn't polly's fault.
这不是Polly的错
She didn't do anything.
她什么都没做
Nothing's happened.I'm just getting her some water.
没什么事 我只是来给她倒水
Is she talking?
她说话了吗?
Did she say where kelly is?
她有说Kelly在哪吗?
We're working on it.
我们正在问
Agent charill,when you said we all grew up together,something struck me.
Charill 当你说到我们一起长大时 我突然想起一件事
What's that?
什么?
We all played football together.
我们都一起玩橄榄球
Don,pete,even chief yates.
Don和Pete 甚至 Chief Yates
We were all on the last championship football team.
我们都在最后一届冠军队伍中
The championship game's tonight.
冠军赛就是今晚了
Polly,can you tell us were kelly seymour is?
Polly 能告诉我们Kelly Seymour在哪吗?
Where's the water?
水呢?
Hutch,do you mind if I--
Hutch 你介意我...
no,please.
请便
Hi,polly.
嗨 Polly
My name is jj.
我叫JJ
I grew up in east allegheny,just right up the road.
我在Allegheny东区长大 就在公路上段
I was captain of the varsity soccer team my senior year.
我第二年就当上了学校足球队的队长
It got me a scholarship to pittsburgh.
这也让我取得了Pittsburgh的奖学金
It was a pretty good school,
一个很好的学校
but it's not exactly penn state.
但不是宾州大学
I know that's where you're going because your mom told me.
我知道你要去那里 你妈妈说的
You know,your mom carried a picture of you
你知道吗 是你妈妈拿着你的照片
all the way up to the fbi academy in quantico,virginia
一路走到我们在 维吉尼亚州Guantico的FBI总部
so that me and these agents here could help find you.
我们才能帮忙找到你
And,believe me,she was not leaving until we said we'd come.
相信我 我们不答应来的话 她是决不会走的
So,no matter what happened over the past 6 days...
所以 无论这六天内发生了什么...
no matter what...
无论怎样...
this will all be a memory someday...
这些都将过去
but you will always have a mother that loves you that much.
但你的妈妈会永远爱你
I want to show you a photograph,polly.
我给你看张照片 Polly
I want you to look at the men in the picture
我要你看着照片里的人
and tell me if you see the man that did this to you.
告诉我们是否看见那个坏人
Ok?
好吗?
Ok.
好
It's ok.
没事的
We were so hungry...
我们当时饿坏了...
so thirsty...
渴死了...
so cold.
又冻僵了
He wants us to do it?
他要我们来做?
If that's what it takes to get out of this alive--
如果只有那么做 我们才能活着出去...
no way,I can'T.
不行 我做不到
You don't have a choice.
你没得选择
I can'T.I can'T.
我不能 不能
Listen,it's like like those soccer players who crashed in the andes.
听着 就像是那些被困在 安第斯山脉的足球运动员
They were starving,they had no food,nothing to eat except for their friends o had died.
他们饥饿 没有食物 除了他们死去的朋友
They were good people,but they didn't have a choice.
他们都是好人 但没有选择
They did what they had to do.
必须这么做
You killed her.
你杀了她
I didn't have any choice.
我没有其他选择
They had already decided to...
她们已经决定...
but it wasn't polly's fault.
这不是Polly的错
It was him.
是他的错
He said we had to choose.
他说我们必须作出抉择
Who was he,brooke?Who made you choose?
他是谁 Brooke? 谁让你们作出抉择?
I never saw him.
我从没看到过他
He made us...
他让我们...
choose.
选择
Who did?
谁?
Good job.
做得好
Hutch,it's the guy that found the soccer jerseys.
Hutch 发现队服的就是他
It's the garbage man.
那个垃圾工人
Marcus younger.
Marcus Younger
Polly just id'd him.
Polly刚刚指出了他
He was the star of our team.
他是我们队中的明星
Blew his knee out in the first quarter of the championship.
在冠军赛第一节时 摔伤了膝盖
Lost his fulbright scholarship to notre dame.
失去了去Notre Dame的 Fullbright奖学金机会
Do you know where he lives?
他住哪里?
Come on.
快点
Clear!
没人!
Guys.
伙计们
There's a storm cellar outside.
外面有地下室
Don't move!
不许动!
I got him.
我逮到他了
Marcus younger?
Marcus Younger?
Fbi.
FBI
I never touched her.
我没有碰过她
Put your hands where I can see them.
把手放在我看得见的地方
I never hurt them.
我从没有伤害她们
Get up,marcus.
起来 Marcus
I never even came into the room,jeff.
我甚至没进来过 Jeff
They did this.
是他们做的
Brooke and polly.
Brooke和Polly
All I did was show them who they really are,
我只是让她们显露了真正的自己
what they were truly capable of.
她们能做出什么
People pretending to be decent.
人们都假装善良
When it came down to it,they,uh...
但当危难时刻...
they reacted just the way I knew they would.
他们就正如我预料般地...
They turned on each other.
互相攻击
Just like when I got hurt.
就像我受伤时一样
You all couldn't wait to run over me,to take my position,to take my life...
你们都迫不及待地跨过我 占领我的位置 我的生活...
and to forget all about me.
完全遗忘了我
Marcus,I'm not going to ask you again.
Marcus 我不会再说第二遍
Get up.
起来!
You don't know what it's like,jeff.
你不知道那是什么样 Jeff
You all have lives,and I just cleaned up after you.
你们都有生活 而我却收拾残局
Now,you have to clean up after me.
现在 要换你们收拾残局了
-You get him out of here. -let's go.
- 把他带出去 - 快走
***********************  ***self
"因不得不超越自我之故 人类终极的选择
this ********************************to love or the hat
是创造或者毁灭 爱或者恨"
***************************
Eric Fromm
Can't sleep?
睡不着?
You can't imagine the pressures a small town creates.
你不能想象在小镇有多大压力
To play,to win,everyone pushing,everyone watching,I hated it.
比赛 胜利 每个人都较劲 每个人都在看着你 我讨厌这些
Why did you play?
为什么要参加呢?
Athletic scholarship was the only way I was getting to college.
我只能靠体育奖学金上大学
It was my only way out.
我只有这一条出路
Besides,having a thick skin when it comes to pressure
另外 做这份工作 压力来临时
is a good thing in this line of work,right?
最需要坚强的外壳 不是吗?
You did exceptional work the last couple of days.
这几天你的表现非常出色
Thank you.
谢谢
It's nice to be noticed.
很高兴被认同
Yeah.We don't usually,do we?
我们不常注意你吗?
Eh,it's all right.
没关系
It's not why I do it.
不是因为这个 我才这么做
Have you ever thought about taking the classes,becoming a profiler?
你有想过接受培训 成为分析师吗?
No.No.
没有
I admire what you guys do,but I like my role.
我很敬佩你们的工作 但我喜欢自己的角色
I like being the person the family can turn to.
我愿意做让家人依靠的那个人
Being the voice the poor,
向大众发布消息
the over-worked homicide detective can call when he runs out of leads.
当过劳的杀人犯侦探没有线索时 我还能提供点信息
Really?
真的吗?
Yeah.
恩
I thought everyone wanted to be a profiler.
我还以为每人都想做分析师
Sorry.
对不起
What's all of that?
那是什么?
New cases.
新的案子
I got to figure out where going to next.
我得看看接下来要去哪里
Hey,wait a minute,we're the profilers.I thought we made those decisions.
等等 我们是分析师 这是我们的决定吧
Sure you do.
当然
All right.Well,I'm going to find someplace to get some sleep.
好的 我找个地方睡觉
-Yeah,good luck with that. -Thanks.
- 好好睡吧 - 谢谢